GUANQUN LIU

Phone: (+86) 13793606086 \diamond Email: liuguanqun0405@gmail.com LinkedIn \diamond Github

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My major research interests lie at the intersection of AI and medical signal processing, particularly in 3D/4D medical imaging, exploring advanced machine learning techniques to interpret and analyze complex imaging data, such as structural segmentation, shape delineation, and lesion diagnosis. Besides, I am also interested in combined modeling between medical signals and large language models in assisting clinical diagnosis and drug discovery. I aim to contribute to the advancement of AI-driven tools that can transform clinical practice and improve patient's quality of life.

EDUCATION

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL), Switzerland

Aug 2024

MSc in Computer Science

• **Grade**: 5.36/6.0 (Top 15%)

• Related courses: Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Image Processing, Applied Biostatistics, Modern Natural Language Processing

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University (HKPU), Hong Kong

Jul 2021

BEng (Hons) in Electronic and Information Engineering

• **Grade**: 3.71/4.0 (Top 10%)

• Related courses: Medical Imaging, Image Processing and Pattern Recognition, Digital Signal Processing

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Master Thesis Project

Feb 2024 - Jul 2024

Supervisors: Dr. Jiancheng Yang, Prof. Pascal Fua

CVLab, EPFL

- · Title: JointAtlas: Deformable Template-Based Implicit Method for Joint Segmentation-Appearance Modeling in Cardiac Images [Report]
- · Explored the feasibility of mapping cardiac structures' segmentation and appearance through generative mapping, simulating the imaging process from the human body to paired task structures.
- · Proposed JointAtlas based on Deep Implicit Field (DIF) and deformable latent templates, this model can represent any cardiac structure by deforming the closest latent template in test-time optimization.
- · Proposed a 1-1 Supervised Template Learning mechanism in training that expands the representation diversity of latent templates.
- · Result: JointAtlas performs remarkable visible structural alignment between tasks and showed superior performance compared to other deformable template-based models in segmentation (Dice score enhanced by $\sim 20\%$ and $\sim 5\%$ on MMWHS MRI and CT dataset respectively).

Research Assistant

Feb 2023 - Jul 2023

Supervisors: Dr. Pol del Aquila Pla, Prof. Michaël Unser

Biomedical Imaging Group, EPFL

 \cdot $\it Title$: Deep Neural Networks to Reconstruct Super-Resolution MRI for 3D Modeling [Report]

- · Designed the Single Acquisition Isotropic Resolution (SAIR) MRI acquisition pipeline, including a sample-specific data processing block with a Gaussian-approximated PSF simulating the imaging process and multi-view through-plane rotations for data augmentation, a self-supervised U-Net model for super-resolution.
- Designed a robust generation mechanism using Fourier Burst Accumulation (FBA) synthesis on multiple rotated SAIR predictions.
- · Designed a Pydicom-based SAIR data converter to allow DICOM metadata processing and transform SAIR's prediction from tensors to standard DICOM files.
- Result: SAIR model's performance in multi-sample testing on reconstruction metrics (PSNR, SSIM) significantly exceeded (>10%) those of cubic spline interpolation for super-resolution. FBA algorithm enhanced prediction robustness and reduced noise effectively, improving the metrics by $\sim 1.5\%$ compared to SAIR without FBA.

Computer Vision Intern

Aug 2022 - Jan 2023

Supervisors: Zoltan Facius, Dr. Alexander Gatto

Stuttgart Technology Center, Sony

- · Title: Deep Learning-Based Specular Highlight Removal in Surgical Images [Link]
- · Collected an endoscopic specular highlight dataset of 3,000+ images with surgery frames from the LapGyn dataset and Sony's data center, filtered and normalized by OpenCV and torchvision.
- · Proposed an endoscopic specular-free generator composed of a two-stage network: AttentiveGAN for specular removal; an LGNet for removal inpainting based on AttentiveGAN's result guided with correction mask from a color-distribution specular detection algorithm.
- · Collected an endoscopic specular-free dataset according to feedback from medical experts on the generator results. Retrained the *AttentiveGAN* to obtain an endoscopic specular highlight removal model.
- · **Result**: The generator achieved 86% correction rate in medical experts' testing, strongly supporting the visual module. The generator and *AttentiveGAN* are adopted by the Tokyo headquarters.

Bachelor Thesis Project

Jan 2021 - June 2021

Supervisor: Prof. Kenneth K.M. LAM

HKPU

- · Title: Real-time Emotion Recognition System
- · Designed a real-time facial recognition module based on AdaBoost algorithm and OpenCV library and an emotion recognition model based on a residual CNN network.
- · Developed an interactive user interface with PyQt library showing real-time emotion recognition results with a multi-face capturing function.
- · **Result**: The emotion recognition model achieved a Top-10 comparable performance in the Kaggle contest on the FER2013 dataset.

ACHIEVEMENTS

HKSAR Government Fund – Reaching Out Award	2020.06
Wong Tit-Shing Student Exchange Scholarship	2019.06
Dean's Honours List	2018.10

SKILLS

Programming Languages	Python, C++, R, Go, Scala, JavaScript, MATLAB
Machine Learning Tools	Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras, scikit-learn, Hugging Face
Image Processing Tools	OpenCV, Pydicom, scikit-image, Pillow
Software Engineering	Version Control, Docker Packaging, Database Management
Languages	Chinese(Native), English(C2), French(A2), Japanese(Beginner)